<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Values on devpaint</title>
    <link>http://www.ahri.net/tags/values/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Values on devpaint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ahri.net/tags/values/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>When to stop caring?</title>
      <link>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/when-to-stop-caring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ahri.net/2014/02/when-to-stop-caring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received some bad news about an estranged friend before I went on holiday and
my first reaction was really &amp;ldquo;should I even care?&amp;rdquo;, see; the estrangement was
pretty mutual and was the result of what I see as profound differences in our
respective approaches to friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to dig all that up, having spent a long time getting to grips with
it and accepting that some relationships just don&amp;rsquo;t work. It really took a long
time to stop thinking about my friend and feeling hurt about what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back on topic; I had this bad news and it stirred all these feelings up, and
my defensive reaction was simply that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care: so I&amp;rsquo;d try not to. I had
a good holiday but I did dwell on it in-between having fun: am I really being
honest with myself here? Can I really just ignore this bad thing that&amp;rsquo;s
happened? Let&amp;rsquo;s bear in mind here; the bad thing is completely not his fault so
it feels completely unjust to mix that up with the things for which I do hold
him accountable; those actions and inactions that led up to the split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to find an answer within myself to the question I&amp;rsquo;ve asked; I
can&amp;rsquo;t switch my feelings on and off, and I can&amp;rsquo;t stop caring or wanting to help
even if I (cynically) feel that I&amp;rsquo;ll end up disappointed that he&amp;rsquo;s not
magically become a friend I want to have. So I&amp;rsquo;ll help where I can and I&amp;rsquo;ll
hope anyway. I can&amp;rsquo;t see any other way that works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>